Guide to the Robert W. Clower Papers, circa 1916-2000 and undated
Robert W. Clower papers circa 1916-2000 and undated
- Writings Series, 1949-1999 and undated
  - Correspondence with J. A. Galbraith about Alfred Marshall on banks, Aug. 1975
  - Notes and typescripts on ideal coordination, 1975 and undated
  - "U.S. Trade Policy: Signs of Change?" and cover letter dated Sept. 1978.
  - 1980 paper by Clower; Friedman's "Crime of 1873," 1989;paper by Hicks
  - Typescripts and miscellaneous material, 1985-1999
  - Conferences and miscellaneous materials, 1986-1989
  - Early undated typescripts and notes, and draft of monetary theory paper with Peter Howitt, 1992
  - Various papers by Keynes, Patinkin, Samuelson, on cash-in-advance, axiomatics, and foundations, 1990-1994 and undated
  - Papers with Howitt, 1998; lecture on Say's Law, 1995; dialogue with Patinkin and Leijonhufvud, 1998; Strotz, 1968
  - Drafts, data, notes, correspondence with Peter Howitt for paper entitled "Emergence of Economic Organization"
- Teaching Materials Series, 1967-1991
  Examinations, reading lists, coursepaks, and other materials from classes taught by Clower at Northwestern, UCLA, and other institutions. Arranged by topic, or in random order, as received originally.
  - Examinations Subseries (Box 5)
    - Macroeconomics, 1967-1976
    - Monetary Economics
    - International Trade
    - Microeconomics
    - Prelims
  - Reading Lists Subseries
    - Money, 1968-1985
    - Reading lists, exams, lecture notes, 1972-1991 (Box 6)
    - Microeconomics, undated
    - Macroeconomics, undated
    - Exams, lecture notes, undated
  - Coursepaks and Other Course Materials Subseries
    - Two cassette tapes, 1972(Restricted - use copies must be made)
    - Economics coursepaks, 1975, 1984
    - Coursepaks, 1975, 1977, 1979
    - Coursepaks, 1977, 1979, 1983, 1986
    - Econ 170: Winter 1981
    - Econ 171: Industrial Organization, Fall 1981-1982
    - Econ 262: Monetary Theory (taught at UCLA), 1982
- Printed Material Series, 1957-1998
  Books, articles, and lectures by Clower and others. Arranged by year.
  - Book introduction to mathematical economics with D. Bushaw, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Intermountain Economic Review:
    - "Notes on the Theory of Markets," by Leijonhufvud, Fall 1970
    - "Say's Principle, What It Means and Doesn't Mean: Part I," Clower and Leijonhufvud, Fall 1973
    - "Reflections on Science and Economics," Robert Clower, Spring 1974
  - Program for History of Economics Society meeting, 1998 (Clower gave presidential address)
  - "Existence Values and Compensable Damages: Judicial Reliance on Empty Economic Concepts," 1992